Guide to the J.P. (John Paul) Smith papers M1894
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
J.P. (John Paul) Smith papers
ca. 1927-1970
M1894
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
1.75 Linear feet (4 manuscript boxes)
J.P. Smith worked on the development of the television at Radio Corporation of America (RCA). This collection contains mostly his early papers and schematics.
Biographical
John Paul Smith (frequently referred to as J.P.) was born in 1905 and received a Bachelor of Science degree in Electrical Engineering in 1927 from Texas A & M College. Upon graduation he joined General Electric in Schenectady where Ernest Alexanderson led the six person television research group, which broadcast a 24 line television signal in 1928 from its station WGY. WGY produced and transmitted the first television drama, “The Queen’s Messenger.” Smith worked on carrier current and early television circuits at GE. With the merger of the television interests of GE, Westinghouse, and RCA in 1930, Mr. Smith moved to Camden, New Jersey to work as a television development engineer at RCA Victor, “where he worked on studio and terminal equipment, specializing in sync generators” (quoted from his resume). Smith worked at Camden on a number of television projects. During World War II Smith seems to have worked in radar and communications primarily. In 1947 Smith resumed his work on television and was focused a great deal on broadcast transmission equipment, especially mobile broadcasting. From 1949 until about 1962 Smith worked on color television on a wide variety of important technical issues. He also trained RCA television dealers on the television sets they were selling. For the rest of his career until he retired in 1971 he worked on a number of diverse government contracts and on satellite communications in such fields as ground stations and image perceptibility and clarity.
Access to Collection
Open for research; material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use.
Acquisition Information
This collection was purchased by Stanford University, Special Collections in January, 2012.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains articles, notes, schematics, photographs, blueprints, and slides related to the development of the television.
Radio Corporation of America (RCA).; Smith, John Paul, 1905-
- RCA: Schematic Wiring Diagrams of 120-line Television Amplifier Terminal Equipment, circa 1932 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- RCA: Resistance-Coupled Picture Frequency Amplifiers for Television Circuits, 1932-09-20 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- RCA: Electrical Synchronizing Generator Using Multivibrators, 1933-08-28 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- RCA: Counter Circuit Timer for Television Synchronizing Signal Generator, 1940-01-05 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- RCA: Ground Clutter Reduction Using the Storage Tube, 1946-07-15 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Graph: Length of uniform Transmission line determination, circa 1940 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- RCA: An Evaluation of Photographic Image Quality, 1962-12-14 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- RCA: Dynamic Regulation of Image Orthicon Beam current, 1963-12-31 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous graphs, blueprints, articles, reprints, notes (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Extensions of Image Sensor Capabilities (with photographs) (Box 1, Folder 10)
- RCA: Television Field Pick-up Equipment, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- RCA: Television High Voltage R-F Supplies, 1946-08-15 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- RCA: Design and Operation of the Television Carrier Synchronizing Equipment, 1949-02-14 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Reprint: A Method of Measuring the Optical Sine-Wave Spatial Spectrum of Television Image Display Devices, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- RCA: Vertical Aperture Equalizer Servo Instruction Manual, 1957-08-17 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- RCA: A High-Definition Television Simulator, 1958-07-01 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- RCA: The Potential of Television Technique in Medicine, 1967-11-20 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Synchronizing Generator papers for RCA review article (Box 2, Folder 7)
- RCA: Synchronizing Generator, Instructions (Box 2, Folder 8)
- RCA: Television Camera Equipment Catalog, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- J.P. Smith patents, 1936-1957 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- General Engineering Instruction: Patents, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Vacuum tube articles and data, 1927-1929 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- "Television and Voice Broadcast equipment...," J. P. Smith, 1929-07-23 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- WTAW: First football broadcast articles, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- RCA: Synchronizing Signal and Blanking Impulse Generator (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Miscellaneous photographs (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous photographs (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous blueprints (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Facts about the Camden Plant RCA Manufacturing Company (Box 3, Folder 4)
- J.P. Smith Retirement material, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- J.P. Smith diploma from Institute of Radio Engineers, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- J.P. Smith Personal Data Summary (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Slide Carousel #1: Early TV Equipment From 1923 to 1930 (Half-box 4, Folder 1)
- Slide Carousel #2: The Early Shows. (1-??), Victor Talking Machine (2-17 to 2-36), RCA 60 Line TV (2-37 to 2-49), Our Competition in 1931 (2-50 to 2-104), The RCA 120 LineField Test (2-105 to 2-114), Iconoscope Camera Tube (2-115 to 2-140) (Half-box 4, Folder 2)
- Slide Carousel #3: Field Tests By NBC in NY (3-1 to 3-27), Camden TV Engineers (3-28 to 3-50), The Amtorg Project. (3-51 to 3-86), Excerpts From RCA Television Publications (3-87 to 3-134), About The Year 441 Lines Became The RMA Standard (Half-box 4, Folder 3)
- Slide Carousel #4: About The Year 441 Lines Became The RMA Standard, The Fall Of ’39 TV Terminal Equipment “Rogues Gallery”. (4-11 to 4-28), TV At The New York World’s Fair Of 1939 (4-29 to 4-32), The Washington DC Field Tests Of RCA Portable TV Equipment (4-33 to 4-49), The RCA Block Equipment (4-50 to 4-52), Other Important Television Events In 1941 (4-53 to 4-62), Construction Begins On The RCA Laboratories, Princeton, N. J. (4-63 to 4-67), Laying Of The Cornerstone At RCA Laboratories On November 15, 1941 (4-68 to 4-83), NBC TV People in the Mid-40s (4-84 to 4-102), Engineering Department: Telephone Directory (4-120 to 4-126) (Half-box 4, Folder 4)